<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Marcus Vechiato</title>
    <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Marcus Vechiato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Seven Books on Managing Technical Debt</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/7-books-managing-technical-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/7-books-managing-technical-debt/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing technical debt is crucial for maintaining the efficiency, security, and scalability of IT systems. It&amp;rsquo;s important to recognize that technical debt encompasses not only software but also infrastructure, security, and organizational processes. Addressing technical debt holistically ensures that an organization can innovate effectively while maintaining robust and secure operations. To help you navigate the complexities of technical debt, I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled a list of books that offer valuable insights and practical strategies for managing technical debt across various aspects of IT, including infrastructure and security.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Learning eBPF: Programmatically Extend the Linux Kernel</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-learning-ebpf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-learning-ebpf/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2023 by Liz Rice
Learning eBPF: Programming the Linux Kernel for Enhanced Observability, Networking, and Security
Learning eBPF Introduction In the realm of cloud-native infrastructure, eBPF (extended Berkeley Packet Filter) has emerged as a revolutionary technology. By allowing developers to write custom code that dynamically changes kernel behavior, eBPF has paved the way for a new generation of security, observability, and networking tools. In &amp;ldquo;Learning eBPF: Programming the Linux Kernel for Enhanced Observability, Networking, and Security,&amp;rdquo; Liz Rice provides a comprehensive guide to understanding and utilizing eBPF.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CNCF Falco Graduation - Another step in your Shift-Left Journey</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20240307-cncf-falco-graduation---another-step-in-your-shift-left-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20240307-cncf-falco-graduation---another-step-in-your-shift-left-journey/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Falco Enhances Container Security with Real-time Threat Detection In today&amp;rsquo;s digital landscape, containerised applications have become the cornerstone of modern software development, offering scalability, portability, and efficiency. However, with the proliferation of containers, security concerns have also escalated. Ensuring the security of containerized environments is paramount to safeguarding sensitive data and maintaining the integrity of applications. To address these challenges, the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) has introduced Falco, an open-source runtime security project designed to provide real-time threat detection for containers and Kubernetes environments.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from DevSecOps</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-devsecops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-devsecops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2020 by Glenn Wilson
DevSecOps Introduction In the evolving landscape of software development, integrating security within the DevOps framework is crucial. Glenn Wilson&amp;rsquo;s DevSecOps offers a comprehensive guide on how to embed security practices into DevOps, ensuring robust and secure software delivery. This book emphasizes a layered approach to DevSecOps, aiming to align security with agile and continuous delivery methodologies.
Summary Part I: Foundations of DevSecOps Chapter 1: DevOps Explained Wilson begins by explaining the origins and principles of DevOps, highlighting its evolution from traditional waterfall methodologies to more agile, continuous delivery models.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
