<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Helm on Marcus Vechiato</title>
    <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/helm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Helm on Marcus Vechiato</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/helm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Insights from End-to-End Automation with Kubernetes and Crossplane</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-end-to-end-automation-with-kubernetes-and-crossplane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-end-to-end-automation-with-kubernetes-and-crossplane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This book is an essential read for cloud architects, platform engineers, infrastructure operators, and Kubernetes enthusiasts. Arun Ramakani expertly navigates the intricate world of infrastructure automation, providing readers with a comprehensive understanding of Crossplane and its integration with Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/end2end_automation_k8s_crossplane.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&#xA;2022 by Arun Ramakani&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B09ZJ1NZRB&#34;&gt;End-to-End Automation with Kubernetes and Crossplane: Develop a control plane-based platform for unified infrastructure, services, and application automation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the ever-evolving landscape of cloud-native infrastructure, Kubernetes has emerged as a dominant force, revolutionising the way organisations deploy and manage applications. However, the complexity of infrastructure automation has often been a bottleneck. Enter Crossplane a powerful extension of Kubernetes designed to bring the same level of automation to infrastructure provisioning and management. In &amp;quot;End-to-End Automation with Kubernetes and Crossplane,&amp;quot; Arun Ramakani guides us through building a control plane-based platform for unified infrastructure, services, and application automation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Learning Helm: Managing Apps on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-learning-helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-learning-helm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I dived into Kubernetes; it felt like stepping into a new world. There were so many moving parts, and I quickly realised the need for effective tools to manage it all. This is where &amp;quot;Learning Helm&amp;quot; by Matt Butcher, Matt Farina, and Josh Dolitsky comes in. The book serves as a comprehensive guide to using Helm, the package manager for Kubernetes. I chose helm because it promised to simplify the complexity of Kubernetes management, and it certainly delivered. Readers can expect to gain a solid understanding of Helm&#39;s capabilities, its architecture, and practical ways to manage Kubernetes applications efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
