<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marcus Vechiato</title>
    <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marcus Vechiato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vechiato.cc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Install and Test DeepSeek R1 Using Ollama</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/deepseek-r1-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/deepseek-r1-homelab/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;DeepSeek R1 is a powerful AI model designed for advanced data analysis and insight extraction. Leveraging the simplicity and flexibility of Ollama, you can get DeepSeek R1 up and running in no time. This guide will walk you through the installation process and demonstrate how to test the model effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into the setup, ensure you have the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ollama Installed&lt;/strong&gt;: Ollama is a platform for running AI models locally. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ollama.com/download&#34;&gt;Download Ollama&lt;/a&gt; and follow the installation instructions for your operating system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Requirements&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimum 16GB RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPU (for optimal performance)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least 10GB of free disk space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;step-1-install-ollama&#34;&gt;Step 1: Install Ollama&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t installed Ollama yet, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculating 3D Print Costs with Spoolman API and Python</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/calculating-3d-print-costs-with-spoolman-api-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/calculating-3d-print-costs-with-spoolman-api-and-python/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;As a 3D printing enthusiast, I&#39;ve often grappled with accurately calculating the cost of my prints. While slicers provide estimates of filament usage, they don&#39;t account for the actual cost of the filament used, especially when dealing with multiple spools or varying filament prices. To solve this, I developed a Python script that calculates the real cost of a 3D print by leveraging the Spoolman API.
In this blog post, I&#39;ll walk you through the motivation behind the project, the features of the script, and how you can use it to accurately estimate your 3D printing costs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Mastering OpenTelemetry and Observability</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-mastering-opentelemetry-and-observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-mastering-opentelemetry-and-observability/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;mastering-opentelemetry-and-observability&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mastering OpenTelemetry and Observability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the fast-paced era of cloud-native systems and distributed architectures, maintaining visibility and reliability across complex infrastructures has become crucial. This led me to explore &lt;em&gt;Mastering OpenTelemetry and Observability&lt;/em&gt; by Steve Flanders. The book is a deep dive into the tools, techniques, and methodologies for achieving robust observability using OpenTelemetry, a leading open-source framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written by a key contributor to OpenTelemetry, this book offers both technical expertise and actionable strategies for leveraging observability to improve system performance and reduce outages. It’s a must-read for anyone looking to enhance their understanding of telemetry data and system diagnostics.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Google Search</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/mastering-google-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/mastering-google-search/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;mastering-google-search-a-guide-for-kids-and-adults&#34;&gt;Mastering Google Search: A Guide for Kids (and Adults!)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet is like a giant library, and Google Search is the tool that helps you find the books you need. Whether you&#39;re coding, solving homework, or just curious about the world, knowing how to use Google effectively is a superpower. Let&#39;s dive into some essential tips and advanced tricks to make your searches smart, precise, and powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-basics&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Basics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose Your Keywords Wisely&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Intro To Python Programming</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-intro-to-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-intro-to-python/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;intro-to-python-programming-beginners-guide-series&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intro To Python Programming: Beginners Guide Series&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a parent and mentor, I’m always on the lookout for resources to inspire and educate young minds. My son recently expressed an interest in learning Python, and I also help kids at a coding club take their first steps into programming. These two motivations led me to John Elder’s &lt;em&gt;Intro to Python Programming&lt;/em&gt;. This book promises to make coding approachable and fun for beginners, which aligns perfectly with my goals. Elder’s conversational tone and hands-on approach provide an excellent foundation for young learners and anyone embarking on their coding journey.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Multi-Cloud Mastery</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-multi-cloud-mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-multi-cloud-mastery/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;multi-cloud-mastery-architecting-secure-and-scalable-kubernetes-systems-and-infrastructures&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Cloud Mastery: Architecting Secure and Scalable Kubernetes Systems and Infrastructures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While managing my own projects that rely on Kubernetes clusters, I often encountered challenges involving scalability, security, and cost optimisation across various cloud providers. These obstacles made me curious about how industry experts approach multi-cloud Kubernetes environments. That’s when I stumbled upon &lt;em&gt;Multi-Cloud Mastery&lt;/em&gt; by Adam Robertson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book dives into the complexities of building and managing Kubernetes clusters across multiple cloud platforms. It offers practical advice for architects, platform engineers, and cloud enthusiasts seeking to harness the potential of multi-cloud strategies. I chose this book to gain deeper insights into a topic that lies at the heart of modern cloud computing—balancing resilience, performance, and cost in a multi-cloud Kubernetes environment.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Club - Quiz Controlled LEDs</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/code-club---quiz-controlled-leds-with-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/code-club---quiz-controlled-leds-with-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;quiz-controlled-leds-with-raspberry-pi&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz Controlled LEDs with Raspberry Pi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a challenge design for someone learning Python with a Raspberry Pi that incorporates asking questions and controlling LEDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a Python-based LED game where players answer questions. Correct answers turn on a green LED, while wrong answers flash a red LED multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;imageobsidiancode_club_thumbjpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/code_club_thumb.jpeg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hardware&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi (with GPIO capabilities)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 green LED for correct answers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 red LED for incorrect answers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 330Ω resistors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breadboard and jumper wires&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;python-concepts&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;else&lt;/code&gt; statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic GPIO control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenge-overview&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenge Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-rules&#34;&gt;Game Rules:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The game asks 5 multiple-choice questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Players respond by entering the correct letter (e.g., A, B, C).
If the answer is correct:
The green LED lights up for 1 second.
The player gets a congratulatory message.
If the answer is incorrect:
The red LED flashes 3 times.
A message tells the player the correct answer.
The game ends with a score summary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-setup-the-leds&#34;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Setup the LEDs&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect the LEDs to two GPIO pins (e.g., GPIO17 and GPIO18).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use resistors to protect the LEDs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect the cathode (short leg) of each LED to the ground (negative -).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/ledquiz_boardbred.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Plaftform Engineering</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-plafform-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-plafform-engineering/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;platform-engineering-a-guide-for-technical-product-and-people-leaders&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platform Engineering: A Guide for Technical, Product, and People Leaders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first came across the idea of platform engineering, I realised how critical it is for scaling organisations to manage shared infrastructure and tools effectively. Camille Fournier and Ian Nowland&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Platform Engineering&lt;/em&gt; goes beyond theory, offering actionable strategies for building cohesive, user-centric platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book resonated with me as someone passionate about improving engineering systems. It provides a structured approach to handling platform challenges, from team organisation to operational excellence. If you&#39;re a leader in the tech space, this guide is a treasure trove of insights to streamline complexity while fostering innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from 20 Easy Raspberry Pi Projects</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-20-easy-raspberry-pi-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-20-easy-raspberry-pi-projects/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;20-easy-raspberry-pi-projects&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20 Easy Raspberry Pi Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first discovered the Raspberry Pi, its versatility felt like a door to endless possibilities. &lt;em&gt;20 Easy Raspberry Pi Projects&lt;/em&gt; by Rui and Sara Santos exemplifies this sentiment by transforming this tiny computer into a toolkit for creativity. The book is packed with practical and entertaining projects, each designed to enhance your programming and electronics skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose this book to explore ways to improve IoT experiments and to inspire ideas for the code club and my son. Whether you’re new to electronics or an experienced maker, the projects in this book will leave you brimming with ideas. Here&#39;s an in-depth look at each project.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Python Basics</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-python-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-python-basics/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;python-basics-a-practical-introduction-to-python-3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python Basics: A Practical introduction to Python 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my son expressed interest in coding, it reignited my passion for introducing Python to others. This book, &lt;em&gt;Python Basics: A Practical Introduction to Python 3&lt;/em&gt;, is now part of the &amp;quot;Code Club&amp;quot; learning list—a collection of resources aimed at helping children at the club (and my son) discover the joy of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written by the Real Python team, this book serves as an excellent entry point for anyone new to programming. It breaks down Python’s fundamentals into digestible lessons, providing real-world examples and coding exercises. Whether you&#39;re a complete beginner or brushing up on basics, this book offers the tools to transform curiosity into skill. Readers can expect to learn the essentials of Python programming and gain confidence in solving practical problems.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Implementing Service Level Objectives</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-implementing-service-level-objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-implementing-service-level-objectives/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;implementing-service-level-objectives-a-practical-guide-to-slis-slos--error-budgets&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementing Service Level Objectives: A Practical Guide to SLIs, SLOs &amp;amp; Error Budgets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reliability is a cornerstone of successful services, but how do we define and measure it effectively? Implementing Service Level Objectives by Alex Hidalgo provides a practical guide to adopting SLO-based approaches, allowing teams to balance user expectations and operational constraints. With its insights into SLIs (Service Level Indicators), SLOs (Service Level Objectives), and error budgets, the book helps bridge the gap between abstract goals and actionable strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Host Your Website for Free as friendly as possible for beginners</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/cloudflare-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/cloudflare-pages/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-host-your-website-for-free-no-git-required&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Host Your Website for Free No Git required!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you’ve just learned HTML and CSS and are eager to put your website online, Cloudflare Pages is an excellent, beginner-friendly way to host your site for free. This post was inspired by my own son, who recently asked me for a way to publish his site that looked a bit more professional than the usual coding platform links. Like him, you might be looking for something simple yet polished to showcase your work. This guide will walk you through the process without needing to know Git or any advanced setups.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from GitHub For Dummies, 2nd Ed</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-github-for-dummies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-github-for-dummies/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;github-for-dummies-2nd-ed&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub For Dummies, 2nd Ed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub has always been a cornerstone of my tinkering projects, whether it’s managing configurations or collaborating on open-source initiatives. When my son asked about contributing to coding projects, I thought of this book: &lt;em&gt;GitHub For Dummies&lt;/em&gt; by Sarah Guthals. Its approachable style and step-by-step tutorials make it an excellent resource, especially for beginners navigating the complexities of version control and collaboration. For anyone curious about starting with GitHub or refining their workflows, this book promises clarity and practical advice.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Outlive</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-outlive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-outlive/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;outlive-the-science-and-art-of-longevity&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outlive: The Science and Art of Longevity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been fascinated by the concept of longevity and what it means to live not just a long life, but a healthy and fulfilling one. When I came across &amp;quot;Outlive: The Science and Art of Longevity&amp;quot; by Peter Attia, I knew it was a must-read. The book delves into the science of prolonging life and improving its quality through proactive health measures. Attia, with his rich background in medicine and personal experiences, offers a comprehensive guide to understanding and implementing strategies for better health and longevity.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Leading Effective Engineering Teams</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-leading-effective-engineering-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-leading-effective-engineering-teams/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;leading-effective-engineering-teams&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leading Effective Engineering Teams&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago, when I found myself managing an engineering team for the first time. The transition from being an individual contributor to a leader was filled with challenges and uncertainties. I wished for a guide that could provide practical advice and real-world examples to navigate this new role effectively. &amp;quot;Leading Effective Engineering Teams&amp;quot; by Addy Osmani is one of the few guides covering this subject. Drawing from over a decade of experience at Google, Osmani uncovers the secrets to engineering effectiveness, efficiency, and team success. This book is a treasure trove of insights for anyone looking to lead a thriving engineering team.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from The Principles of Product Development Flow</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-the-principles-of-product-development-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-the-principles-of-product-development-flow/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;the-principles-of-product-development-flow-second-generation-lean-product-development&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Principles of Product Development Flow: Second Generation Lean Product Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today&#39;s fast-paced and highly competitive market, understanding and optimizing product development processes is crucial. &amp;quot;The Principles of Product Development Flow&amp;quot; by Donald G. Reinertsen offers a comprehensive guide to mastering lean product development. This book provides actionable insights into managing queues, reducing batch sizes, and applying economic principles to enhance product development efficiency. This book is a game-changer for anyone involved in product development. It goes beyond high-level theory and delves into practical, real-life examples, providing a comprehensive approach to achieving efficient and effective product development processes. If you&#39;re looking to transform your product development practices, this book is a must-read.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Watermelon Effect</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/the-watermelon-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/the-watermelon-effect/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;are-your-metrics-hiding-the-truth&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are Your Metrics Hiding the Truth?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The watermelon effect in IT refers to situations where metrics appear green (positive) on the outside but are red (negative) on the inside. This can lead to a false sense of security and overlook underlying issues. Addressing this requires a combination of transparent metrics, honest culture, and actionable insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/green-striped-ripe-watermelon.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

Image by YuliiaKa on Freepik&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-the-watermelon-effect&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding the Watermelon Effect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/watermelon-effect.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

The watermelon effect occurs when surface-level indicators show success while deeper issues remain hidden. This can be due to focusing on vanity metrics that look good but do not provide meaningful insights into actual performance.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Crossplane: The Cloud Native Control Plane</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-crossplane-the-cloud-native-control-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-crossplane-the-cloud-native-control-plane/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;crossplane-the-cloud-native-control-plane&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crossplane: The Cloud Native Control Plane&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Platform Engineering enthusiast, I&#39;ve always been fascinated by the potential of cloud-native technologies to streamline and enhance our workflows. Recently, I picked up &amp;quot;Crossplane: The Cloud Native Control Plane&amp;quot; by Viktor Farcic, and it has been an enlightening journey. This book delves into the intricacies of Crossplane, a project that democratizes the powerful capabilities traditionally reserved for major cloud providers. By abstracting away complexity and allowing for custom control planes, Crossplane stands out as a transformative tool for modern infrastructure management. I chose this book to deepen my understanding of how Crossplane can help create a seamless, scalable, and efficient cloud infrastructure tailored to specific organizational needs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Books on Managing Technical Debt</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/7-books-managing-technical-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/7-books-managing-technical-debt/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Managing technical debt is crucial for maintaining the efficiency, security, and scalability of IT systems. It&#39;s important to recognise that technical debt encompasses not only software but also infrastructure, security, and organisational processes. Addressing technical debt holistically ensures that an organisation can innovate effectively while maintaining robust and secure operations. To help you navigate the complexities of technical debt, I&#39;ve compiled a list of  books that offer valuable insights and practical strategies for managing technical debt across various aspects of IT, including infrastructure and security.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Chaos Engineering: System Resiliency in Practice</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-chaos-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-chaos-engineering/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;chaos-engineering-system-resiliency-in-practice&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaos Engineering: System Resiliency in Practice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember multiple occasions when systems were not down but badly impacted during major events. The scramble to restore service and the subsequent post-mortem meeting highlighted our lack of preparedness for unexpected system failures. The book begins with the history of Chaos Engineering, originating from Netflix. Rosenthal and Jones describe the transition from datacenter architecture to cloud infrastructure, highlighting challenges and the necessity of Chaos Engineering for improving system resiliency. This book delves into the principles and practices of Chaos Engineering, a methodology designed to improve system reliability by intentionally introducing failures. I chose this book to understand how we can better prepare for the unexpected and ensure our systems can withstand and recover from disruptions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Platform Engineering on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-platform-engineering-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-platform-engineering-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;platform-engineering-on-kubernetes&#34;&gt;Platform Engineering on Kubernetes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Platform Engineering on Kubernetes&amp;quot; by Mauricio Salatino provides a comprehensive guide to leveraging Kubernetes for platform engineering. This book explores the intricacies of building and maintaining platforms on top of Kubernetes, focusing on the needs of development teams and the challenges of cloud-native environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/book_platform_engineering_kubernetes.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2022 by Mauricio Salatino&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/mindmap_platform_engineering_k8s.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-rise-of-platforms-on-top-of-kubernetes&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The Rise of Platforms on Top of Kubernetes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter introduces the concept of platforms and their significance. It explains why platforms are essential for organisations and discusses the advantages of building platforms on top of Kubernetes. The chapter also outlines the challenges associated with platform engineering and the need for a &amp;quot;walking skeleton&amp;quot; to demonstrate platform concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from 48 Laws of Power</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-48-laws-of-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-48-laws-of-power/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;the-48-laws-of-power&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 48 Laws of Power&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I encountered the concept of power dynamics in a workplace. A seemingly harmless comment from a colleague turned into a lesson in hierarchy and influence. This personal experience nudged me towards exploring how power operates in various facets of life. It led me to &lt;em&gt;The 48 Laws of Power&lt;/em&gt; by Robert Greene, a book that delves deep into the mechanics of power, manipulation, and strategy. Greene&#39;s work is a comprehensive guide on understanding and navigating power structures, making it a must-read for anyone looking to thrive in competitive environments. I chose this book because it offers practical and historical insights into power, helping readers recognize and apply these principles in their own lives.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Learning eBPF</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-learning-ebpf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-learning-ebpf/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-ebpf-programmatically-extend-the-linux-kernel&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning eBPF: Programmatically Extend the Linux Kernel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the realm of cloud-native infrastructure, eBPF (extended Berkeley Packet Filter) has emerged as a revolutionary technology. By allowing developers to write custom code that dynamically changes kernel behavior, eBPF has paved the way for a new generation of security, observability, and networking tools. In &amp;quot;Learning eBPF: Programming the Linux Kernel for Enhanced Observability, Networking, and Security,&amp;quot; Liz Rice provides a comprehensive guide to understanding and utilizing eBPF. This book is essential for developers, system administrators, operators, and students who seek to harness the power of eBPF.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Learning Open Telemetry</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-learning-open-telemetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-learning-open-telemetry/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-opentelemetry-setting-up-and-operating-a-modern-observability-system&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning OpenTelemetry: Setting Up and Operating a Modern Observability System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who has spent countless hours troubleshooting distributed systems, I understand the struggle of trying to untangle metrics, logs, and traces spread across multiple tools. That’s why &lt;em&gt;Learning OpenTelemetry&lt;/em&gt; by Austin Parker and Ted Young resonated with me. This book introduces OpenTelemetry, a game-changing framework for observability that unifies these disparate signals into a cohesive system. Whether you&#39;re new to observability or a seasoned developer looking to adopt modern practices, this book provides the tools and insights to make your systems more transparent and easier to debug.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Flask Web Development, Second Edition</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-flask-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-flask-web-development/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;flask-web-development&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flask Web Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up &amp;quot;Flask Web Development&amp;quot; by Miguel Grinberg as part of my journey to deepen my understanding of web application development with Python. Having some experience with Django, I was curious to explore the micro-framework approach offered by Flask, known for its simplicity and flexibility. This book promised a hands-on guide to building web applications using Flask, which I hoped would help me apply these concepts in real-world projects.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Misbelief</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-misbelif/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-misbelif/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;misbelief-what-makes-rational-people-believe-irrational-things&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misbelief: What Makes Rational People Believe Irrational Things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I stumbled upon a friend’s social media post that seemed utterly detached from reality. It wasn’t just a quirky opinion or an eccentric idea, but a full-blown conspiracy theory. This experience piqued my interest in understanding how rational individuals could come to hold such irrational beliefs. This curiosity led me to Dan Ariely’s book, &lt;em&gt;Misbelief: What Makes Rational People Believe Irrational Things&lt;/em&gt;. Ariely, a renowned behavioral economist, delves into the psychological underpinnings that drive people down the path of misbelief. This book offers a comprehensive look into the factors that shape our beliefs and why some individuals are more susceptible to false narratives. Readers can expect to gain a deeper understanding of the emotional, cognitive, personality, and social elements that contribute to the formation and persistence of misbeliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CNCF Falco Graduation - Another step in your Shift-Left Journey</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/cncf-falco-graduation---another-step-in-your-shift-left-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/cncf-falco-graduation---another-step-in-your-shift-left-journey/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;falco-enhances-container-security-with-real-time-threat-detection&#34;&gt;Falco Enhances Container Security with Real-time Threat Detection&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today&#39;s digital landscape, containerised applications have become the cornerstone of modern software development, offering scalability, portability, and efficiency. However, with the proliferation of containers, security concerns have also escalated. Ensuring the security of containerized environments is paramount to safeguarding sensitive data and maintaining the integrity of applications. To address these challenges, the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) has introduced Falco, an open-source runtime security project designed to provide real-time threat detection for containers and Kubernetes environments.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitOps Certification</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/certified-gitops-associate-cgoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/certified-gitops-associate-cgoa/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;The CGOA certification was announced in 2023 can now be purchased as of February 21, 2024, but the ability to schedule a CGOA exam will not be available until the end of March 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://training.linuxfoundation.org/certification/certified-gitops-associate-cgoa/&#34;&gt;Certified GitOps Associate (CGOA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience Level:&lt;/strong&gt; Beginner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple-choice Exam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration of Exam 90 Minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certification Valid for 3 Years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Includes 12 Month Exam Eligibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One Retake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDF Certificate and Digital Badge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $ 250 (USD)&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Learning GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-learning-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-learning-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-github-actions-automation-and-integration-of-cicd-with-github&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning GitHub Actions: Automation and Integration of CI/CD with GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is a comprehensive guide on how to leverage GitHub Actions to simplify and automate your continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD) pipelines. Brent Laster does an excellent job of breaking down complex concepts into digestible parts, making this a must-read for anyone looking to enhance their software development workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/learning_github_actions.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2023 by Brent Laster&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/mindmap_learning_github_actions.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Kubernetes Up and Running, 3rd Edition</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-kubernetes-up-and-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-kubernetes-up-and-running/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;kubernetes-up-and-running&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes: Up and Running&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kubernetes: Up and Running&lt;/em&gt; by Brendan Burns, Joe Beda, and Kelsey Hightower is a comprehensive guide to understanding and deploying Kubernetes, the leading platform for container orchestration. This book provides a thorough introduction to Kubernetes, covering its architecture, deployment, and management, along with practical examples and use cases. It&#39;s an essential resource for anyone looking to leverage Kubernetes for scalable, resilient, and manageable applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/kubernetes_up_and_running.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2022 by Brendan Burns, Joe Beda, Kelsey Hightower &amp;amp; Lachlan Evenson&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Adopting InnerSource</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-adopting-innersource/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-adopting-innersource/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Adopting InnerSource: Principles and Case Studies&amp;quot; by Danese Cooper and Klaas-Jan Stol explores how companies can leverage the principles of open-source software development within their own organisations. InnerSource adapts the collaborative, transparent, and community-driven practices of open-source to a corporate environment, fostering innovation and efficiency. This book presents various case studies from companies that have successfully adopted InnerSource, providing practical insights and lessons learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/book_adopting_innersource.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2018 by Danese Cooper &amp;amp; Klaas-Jan Stol&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from End-to-End Automation with Kubernetes and Crossplane</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-end-to-end-automation-with-kubernetes-and-crossplane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-end-to-end-automation-with-kubernetes-and-crossplane/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This book is an essential read for cloud architects, platform engineers, infrastructure operators, and Kubernetes enthusiasts. Arun Ramakani expertly navigates the intricate world of infrastructure automation, providing readers with a comprehensive understanding of Crossplane and its integration with Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/end2end_automation_k8s_crossplane.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2022 by Arun Ramakani&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B09ZJ1NZRB&#34;&gt;End-to-End Automation with Kubernetes and Crossplane: Develop a control plane-based platform for unified infrastructure, services, and application automation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the ever-evolving landscape of cloud-native infrastructure, Kubernetes has emerged as a dominant force, revolutionising the way organisations deploy and manage applications. However, the complexity of infrastructure automation has often been a bottleneck. Enter Crossplane—a powerful extension of Kubernetes designed to bring the same level of automation to infrastructure provisioning and management. In &amp;quot;End-to-End Automation with Kubernetes and Crossplane,&amp;quot; Arun Ramakani guides us through building a control plane-based platform for unified infrastructure, services, and application automation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from The DevOps Handbook</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-the-devops-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-the-devops-handbook/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;the-devops-handbook&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The DevOps Handbook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving landscape of software development and IT operations, the principles of DevOps have become essential for organisations striving to enhance their productivity, efficiency, and overall business success. &amp;quot;The DevOps Handbook: Second Edition&amp;quot; by Gene Kim, Jez Humble, Patrick Debois, and John Willis offers a comprehensive guide to implementing DevOps practices. This book provides valuable insights into the principles, methodologies, and case studies that illustrate the transformative power of DevOps in modern enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tower Sep-Nov2023</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/tower-sep2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/tower-sep2023/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Dive into my journey of experimenting with hydroponics! Over the past few months, I&#39;ve tracked the key metric: pH, PPM, and growth stages for cultivating lettuce. This post outlines my progress, adjustments, and outcomes, complete with a timeline of photos and data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lettuce	ideal PH 5.5 – 6.5 PPM 560 – 840&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;PH&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;PPM&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;Photo&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;11/11/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;6.4&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;580&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/tower231111.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;04/11/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;5.89&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;332-640&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/tower231104.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;29/10/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;450&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/tower231029.jpeg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;22/10/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;6.04&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;640&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/tower231022.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;14/10/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;6.05&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;650&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/tower231014.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;07/10/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;5.81&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;680&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/tower231007.jpeg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;30/09/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;5.95&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;770&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/tower230930.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;22/09/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;770&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/tower230922.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;17/09/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/tower230917.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;10/09/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;n/a&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/tower230923.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Economics for the Common Good</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-economics-for-the-common-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-economics-for-the-common-good/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;economics-for-the-common-good&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economics for the Common Good&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading &amp;quot;Economics for the Common Good&amp;quot; by Jean Tirole has been a transformative experience for me. As someone who is deeply interested in the intersection of economics and society, this book provided a comprehensive and nuanced exploration of how economic principles can be applied to achieve the common good. Tirole, a Nobel Prize-winning economist, delves into various economic theories and their implications for policy-making, societal well-being, and global challenges. I chose this book because of its relevance to contemporary economic issues and its potential to offer valuable insights into how economics can be harnessed for societal benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Cloud FinOps: Collaborative, Real-Time Cloud Value Decision Making</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-cloud-finops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-cloud-finops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;cloud-finops-collaborative-real-time-cloud-value-decision-making&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloud FinOps: Collaborative, Real-Time Cloud Value Decision Making&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the modern era of cloud computing, managing cloud spend efficiently has become crucial for businesses. &amp;quot;Cloud FinOps: Collaborative, Real-Time Cloud Value Decision Making&amp;quot; by J.R. Storment and Mike Fuller delves into the practices and principles of FinOps, a methodology that combines financial management with DevOps to drive accountability and efficiency in cloud spending. This book is an essential read for engineering and finance teams, executives, and FinOps practitioners aiming to optimise their cloud investments.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seedling Aug-Sep23</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/seedling-aug23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/seedling-aug23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Join me as I explore the initial stages of my hydroponics journey! This post captures the progress of lettuce and rocket seedlings over several weeks, with updates on their growth, adjustments to the setup, and visual highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;what&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Photo&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;10/09/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lettuce/Rocket&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/seedling230910.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;05/09/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lettuce/Rocket&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/seedling230923.jpeg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;27/08/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lettuce/Rocket&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/seedling230827.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;25/08/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lettuce/Rocket&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/seedling230825.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;20/08/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lettuce/Rocket&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/seedling230823.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;17/08/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lettuce/Rocket&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/seedling230817.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;14/08/23&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lettuce/Rocket&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/seedling230814.jpeg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from The Staff Engineer&#39;s Path</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-the-staff-engineers-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-the-staff-engineers-path/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;the-staff-engineers-path&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Staff Engineer&#39;s Path&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of technology, career paths often lead to management roles. However, many engineers prefer to remain as individual contributors while advancing their careers. &amp;quot;The Staff Engineer&#39;s Path: A Guide for Individual Contributors Navigating Growth and Change&amp;quot; by Tanya Reilly provides a roadmap for those aiming to excel as senior technical leaders without transitioning into management. This book is an essential guide for engineers looking to elevate their impact and influence within their organizations.
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/the_staff_enginners_path.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2022 by Tanya Reilly&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Prometheus Up &amp; Running</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-prometheus-up-and-running-2nd-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-prometheus-up-and-running-2nd-ed/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;prometheus-up--running-infrastructure-and-application-performance-monitoring-2nd-ed&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prometheus Up &amp;amp; Running: Infrastructure and Application Performance Monitoring, 2nd Ed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When managing modern systems, effective monitoring can make or break your application’s reliability and performance. My own journey with monitoring tools has been one of trial and error, searching for a solution that balances simplicity and power. That’s why I picked up &lt;em&gt;Prometheus: Up &amp;amp; Running (Second Edition)&lt;/em&gt; by Julien Pivotto and Brian Brazil. This book dives deep into Prometheus, an open-source, metrics-based monitoring system, which has become a cornerstone for DevOps teams worldwide. If you&#39;re curious about scaling your infrastructure monitoring or learning Prometheus from scratch, this book provides a comprehensive guide.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on My Presentation at the London SRE Meetup</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/london-sre-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/london-sre-meetup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I recently had the wonderful opportunity to present at the London SRE Meetup, and I&#39;m excited to share the experience with you all. The presentation, titled &amp;quot;Working Together: SRE and Platform Engineering,&amp;quot; focused on the synergy between site reliability engineering and platform engineering to enhance operational efficiencies and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to have engaged with so many knowledgeable professionals and enthusiasts who are passionate about improving systems and operations. The discussions and interactions were enlightening, and I hope they were as beneficial for attendees as they were for me.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Building Microservices by Sam Newman</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-building-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-building-microservices/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;building-microservices-designing-fine-grained-systems&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building Microservices: Designing Fine-Grained Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Building Microservices&lt;/em&gt; by Sam Newman provides a structured, pragmatic exploration of the subject, with real-world examples and balanced perspectives. The book covers the nuances of adopting microservices, from foundational principles to advanced topics like observability, security, and organizational structure. For anyone navigating the complexities of microservices, this book is a definitive guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/book_building_microservices.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2021 by Sam Newman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-i-foundation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part I: Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;chapter-1-what-are-microservices&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 1: What Are Microservices?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microservices are independently deployable services modeled around business domains. They prioritise flexibility, technology agnosticism, and clear service boundaries while avoiding shared databases. Newman underscores the importance of independent deployability, arguing that it is the most critical characteristic of microservices.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Learning Helm: Managing Apps on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-learning-helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-learning-helm/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-helm-managing-apps-on-kubernetes&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Helm: Managing Apps on Kubernetes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I dived into Kubernetes; it felt like stepping into a new world. There were so many moving parts, and I quickly realised the need for effective tools to manage it all. This is where &amp;quot;Learning Helm&amp;quot; by Matt Butcher, Matt Farina, and Josh Dolitsky comes in. The book serves as a comprehensive guide to using Helm, the package manager for Kubernetes. I chose helm because it promised to simplify the complexity of Kubernetes management, and it certainly delivered. Readers can expect to gain a solid understanding of Helm&#39;s capabilities, its architecture, and practical ways to manage Kubernetes applications efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from The Innovator&#39;s Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-innovators-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-innovators-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;the-innovators-dilemma&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Innovators Dilemma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Innovator&#39;s Dilemma&lt;/em&gt; by Clayton M. Christensen is a seminal work that explores why successful companies often fail when confronted with disruptive technological change. Christensen, through extensive research and real-world examples, provides a framework for understanding the principles of disruptive innovation and offers strategies for managing technological transitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/innovators_dilemma.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2016 by Clayton M. Christensen
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/1633691780&#34;&gt;The Innovator&#39;s Dilemma: When New Technologies Cause Great Firms to Fail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Blink</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-blink/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-blink/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;blink-the-power-of-thinking-without-thinking&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blink: The Power of Thinking Without Thinking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world where decisions are often made in the blink of an eye, understanding the power of these snap judgments is crucial. Malcolm Gladwell&#39;s &amp;quot;Blink: The Power of Thinking Without Thinking&amp;quot; delves into the science and psychology behind these rapid decisions, revealing how they can be both incredibly accurate and dangerously flawed. This book is a fascinating exploration of the unconscious mind and its role in our everyday choices.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Establishing SRE Foundations</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-establishing-sre-foundations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-establishing-sre-foundations/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;establishing-sre-foundations&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establishing SRE Foundations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Establishing SRE Foundations: A Step-by-Step Guide&amp;quot; by Vladyslav Ukis provides a comprehensive framework for implementing Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) in software delivery organisations. Drawing from his extensive experience, Ukis outlines practical steps and methodologies to enhance reliability and operational efficiency in software systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/sre_foundations.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/0137424604&#34;&gt;Establishing SRE Foundations: A Step-by-Step Guide to Introducing Site Reliability Engineering in Software Delivery Organizations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/mindmap_establishing_sre.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Observability Engineering: Achieving Production Excellence</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-observability-engineering-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-observability-engineering-2022/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;observability-engineering&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observability Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving landscape of software development and IT operations, ensuring system reliability and performance is paramount. &amp;quot;Observability Engineering&amp;quot; by Charity Majors, Liz Fong-Jones, and George Miranda provides a comprehensive guide to achieving production excellence through observability. This book explores the principles, practices, and tools necessary to understand and improve system behavior, making it an essential read for software engineers and site reliability engineers (SREs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/observability_engineering.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2022 by Charity Majors &amp;amp; Liz Fong-Jones &amp;amp; George Miranda&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Fluent Python, second edition</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-fluent-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-fluent-python/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;fluent-python-clear-concise-and-effective-programming&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fluent Python: Clear, Concise, and Effective Programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our deep dive into &lt;em&gt;Fluent Python&lt;/em&gt; by Luciano Ramalho. In this post, we&#39;ll explore key concepts and insights from the book that will help you master Python programming. Whether you&#39;re a beginner or an experienced developer, this book offers valuable lessons on writing idiomatic Python code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fluent Python&lt;/em&gt; by Luciano Ramalho is a comprehensive guide that delves into the depths of Python programming, offering insights and practical advice on writing idiomatic and efficient Python code.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Building a Second Brain</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-building-a-second-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-building-a-second-brain/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;building-a-second-brain&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building a Second Brain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I found myself overwhelmed by the sheer volume of information I was trying to manage daily. Articles, books, emails, and notes piled up, creating a chaotic mental space that hindered my productivity and creativity. When I came across Tiago Forte’s &lt;em&gt;Building a Second Brain&lt;/em&gt;, it felt like a lifeline. This book promises to help readers organize their digital lives and unlock their creative potential through a methodical approach to personal knowledge management. Intrigued by the idea of creating a digital system to support my thinking and memory, I dived in. This book offers a structured method to capture, organize, distill, and express information, ultimately transforming how we interact with and leverage our knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Team Topologies: Organizing Business and Technology Teams for Fast Flow</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-team-topologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-team-topologies/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;team-topologies&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Topologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Team Topologies: Organising Business and Technology Teams for Fast Flow&amp;quot; by Matthew Skelton and Manuel Pais offers a novel approach to structuring technology teams to achieve high performance and rapid delivery. The authors present practical frameworks and insights to help organisations navigate the complexities of modern software development by optimising team interactions and responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/team_topologies_book.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2019 by Matthew Skelton and Manuel Pais&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B07W1667D7&#34;&gt;Team Topologies: Organizing Business and Technology Teams for Fast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Working Backwards: Insights, Stories, and Secrets from Inside Amazon</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-working-backwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-working-backwards/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;working-backwards&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working Backwards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Working Backwards: Insights, Stories, and Secrets from Inside Amazon&amp;quot; by Colin Bryar and Bill Carr offers an insider’s perspective on the unique principles and processes that have driven Amazon&#39;s success. The authors, both former Amazon executives, provide a detailed account of how the company&#39;s culture and methodologies can be applied to achieve extraordinary results in any organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/working_backwards.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2021 by Colin Bryar &amp;amp; Bill Carr&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Ego Free Leadership: Ending the Unconscious Habits that Hijack Your Business</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-ego-free-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-ego-free-leadership/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;ego-free-leadership-ending-the-unconscious-habits-that-hijack-your-business&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ego Free Leadership: Ending the Unconscious Habits that Hijack Your Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ego Free Leadership&lt;/em&gt; by Brandon Black and Shayne Hughes provides a powerful exploration into how ego-driven behaviours can derail leadership and organisational success. Through the story of Brandon Black’s tenure as CEO of Encore Capital and his collaboration with executive coach Shayne Hughes, the book offers profound insights into overcoming ego to foster a culture of authenticity and high performance.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from No rules rules: Netflix and the culture of reinvention</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-no-rules-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-no-rules-rules/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;no-rules-rules&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Rules Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &amp;quot;No Rules Rules: Netflix and the Culture of Reinvention,&amp;quot; Reed Hastings and Erin Meyer explore the unique and unconventional management philosophies that have made Netflix one of the most innovative and successful companies in the world. By prioritising freedom and responsibility over traditional corporate controls, Netflix has continuously reinvented itself to adapt to the changing needs of its global audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/no_rules_rules.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2020 by Reed Hastings and Erin Meyer&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Systems Performance: Enterprise and the Cloud, Second Edition</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-systems-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-systems-performance/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;systems-performance&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Systems Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Systems Performance: Enterprise and the Cloud&amp;quot; by Brendan Gregg is a comprehensive guide to understanding and improving the performance of computer systems. The book covers a wide range of topics, from the fundamentals of systems performance to advanced techniques for optimizing various system components. It provides practical methodologies and tools for performance analysis, making it an essential resource for system administrators, developers, and performance engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/systems_performance.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2020 by Brendan Gregg&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Accelerate</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-accelerate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-accelerate/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;accelerate-the-science-of-lean-software-and-devops&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accelerate: The Science of Lean Software and DevOps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Accelerate: The Science of Lean Software and DevOps&amp;quot; by Nicole Forsgren, Jez Humble, and Gene Kim is a pivotal book that delves into the principles of Lean and DevOps to improve software delivery and organisational performance. The authors combine rigorous academic research with practical insights, presenting a comprehensive guide for technology leaders to drive performance improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/book_accelerate.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2018 by Nicole Forsgren, Jez Humble and Gene Kim&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Ask Your Developer</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-ask-your-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-ask-your-developer/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;ask-your-developer&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask Your Developer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the digital age, businesses need to adapt quickly to remain competitive. &amp;quot;Ask Your Developer&amp;quot; by Jeff Lawson, the CEO of Twilio, provides a roadmap for leveraging software developers&#39; expertise to drive innovation and success. Lawson emphasizes the importance of integrating developers into business decision-making processes and creating an environment that fosters creativity and experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/ask_your_developer.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2021 by Jeff Lawson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/mindmap_ask_your_dev.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from DevSecOps</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-devsecops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-devsecops/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;devsecops&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DevSecOps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evolving landscape of software development, integrating security within the DevOps framework is crucial. Glenn Wilson&#39;s &lt;em&gt;DevSecOps&lt;/em&gt; offers a comprehensive guide on how to embed security practices into DevOps, ensuring robust and secure software delivery. This book emphasizes a layered approach to DevSecOps, aiming to align security with agile and continuous delivery methodologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/book_DevSecOps.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2020 by Glenn Wilson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/mindmap_devsecops.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-i-foundations-of-devsecops&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part I: Foundations of DevSecOps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;chapter-1-devops-explained&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 1: DevOps Explained&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilson begins by explaining the origins and principles of DevOps, highlighting its evolution from traditional waterfall methodologies to more agile, continuous delivery models. Key concepts include the three ways (left-to-right process flow, right-to-left feedback, and continuous improvement) and the five ideals (locality and simplicity, focus, flow and joy, improvement of daily work, psychological safety, and customer focus).&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Database Reliability Engineering: Designing and Operating Resilient Database Systems</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-database-reliability-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-database-reliability-engineering/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;database-reliability-engineering-designing-and-operating-resilient-database-systems&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database Reliability Engineering: Designing and Operating Resilient Database Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Database Reliability Engineering&lt;/em&gt; by Laine Campbell and Charity Majors is a comprehensive guide on how to design, build, and manage resilient database systems. The book emphasises the importance of reliability in database operations and introduces the role of a Database Reliability Engineer (DBRE) who combines database expertise with software engineering principles to ensure robust data management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/book_database_reliability.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2017 by Laine Campbell &amp;amp; Charity Majors&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Seeking SRE</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-seeking-sre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-seeking-sre/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;seeking-sre&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seeking SRE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) has become a fundamental practice in ensuring the reliability and efficiency of large-scale production systems. &amp;quot;Seeking SRE: Conversations About Running Production Systems at Scale&amp;quot; by David N. Blank-Edelman offers a comprehensive exploration of SRE practices through a series of insightful essays and interviews. This book serves as an invaluable resource for anyone involved in managing complex systems, from seasoned SREs to those new to the field.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from The Manager&#39;s Path</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-the-managers-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-the-managers-path/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;the-managers-path&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Manager&#39;s Path&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Manager&#39;s Path&lt;/em&gt; by Camille Fournier is a comprehensive guide for those pursuing a career in engineering management. Fournier, drawing from her experiences, provides a structured roadmap for transitioning from an engineer to a manager and beyond. This book is a valuable resource not only for new managers but also for seasoned leaders seeking to refine their skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/the_managers_path.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2017 by Camile Fournier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/1491973897&#34;&gt;The Manager&#39;s Path: A Guide for Tech Leaders Navigating&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Designing Data-Intensive Applications</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-designing-data-intensive-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-designing-data-intensive-applications/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;designing-data-intensive-applications-the-big-ideas-behind-reliable-scalable-and-maintainable-systems&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Designing Data-Intensive Applications: The Big Ideas Behind Reliable, Scalable and Maintainable Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Designing Data-Intensive Applications&lt;/em&gt; by Martin Kleppmann is a comprehensive guide to understanding the principles and architectures behind building reliable, scalable, and maintainable data systems. The book delves into the fundamental concepts of data processing and storage, offering in-depth analysis and practical insights into how to handle data at scale. This book is essential for software engineers, architects, and technical managers who want to build robust data-intensive applications.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Domain-Driven Design Distilled</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-domain-driven-design-distilled/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-domain-driven-design-distilled/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;domain-driven-design-distilled&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Domain-Driven Design Distilled&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the complex world of software development, mastering effective design principles is key to success. Vaughn Vernon&#39;s &amp;quot;Domain-Driven Design Distilled&amp;quot; simplifies the intricate concepts of Domain-Driven Design (DDD), providing a clear path to creating software that truly aligns with business needs. This book breaks down strategic and tactical modeling tools that can transform how software projects are approached and executed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/domain_drive_desing.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2016 by Vaughn Vernon&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Remote: Office not Required</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-remote/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;remote-office-not-required&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remote: Office Not Required&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the days when working from home was a rare privilege, reserved for special circumstances. Fast forward to today, remote work has become a norm, a necessity even, due to technological advancements and recent global events. This shift intrigued me, and it was a recommendation from my friend Eduardo that led me to &amp;quot;Remote: Office Not Required&amp;quot; by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson. This book explores the phenomenon of remote work, its challenges, and its unexpected benefits. Eduardo&#39;s recommendation was timely as I sought to understand how remote work could be effectively implemented and its impact on workplace culture and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from The Five Dysfunctions of a Team</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-the-five-dysfunctions-of-a-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-the-five-dysfunctions-of-a-team/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;the-five-dysfunctions-of-a-team&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Five Dysfunctions of a Team&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book, presented as a leadership fable, delves into the core issues that impede teamwork and provides actionable insights to overcome these challenges. I chose this book to gain a deeper understanding of team dynamics and to find practical strategies to foster a more collaborative environment. You can expect to gain a comprehensive framework for identifying and addressing the common pitfalls that teams face, ultimately leading to improved performance and unity.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using screen for Persistent Terminal Sessions</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/screen/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;screen&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;screen&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;screen&lt;/code&gt; is a terminal multiplexer that allows you to start a session, run commands, and detach from it, keeping the session running in the background. You can later reattach to the session even if the original terminal connection was lost, which is useful for remote tasks that need resilience against disconnections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;basic-commands&#34;&gt;Basic Commands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;start-a-new-session&#34;&gt;Start a New Session&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start a new session with a custom name (e.g., &lt;code&gt;my_session&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ln&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;screen -S my_session
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;run-a-command&#34;&gt;Run a Command&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the screen session, run any long-running command:&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search and identify bad sectors on a storage device using badblocks</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/badblocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/badblocks/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;badblocks&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Badblocks&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;badblocks&lt;/code&gt; command in Linux is used to search for and identify bad sectors on a storage device, such as a hard drive or solid-state drive. It can help detect damaged or faulty sectors that may affect the reliability of the disk and the data stored on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;badblocks&lt;/code&gt; command scans a disk for bad sectors by writing test patterns (usually zeros or ones) to the disk and then reading them back. If the data cannot be read correctly after being written, the sector is considered &amp;quot;bad.&amp;quot; The command then reports the location of these bad sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Continuous Delivery</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-continuous-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-continuous-delivery/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;continuous-delivery&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous Delivery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous Delivery (CD) has revolutionised the way software is developed and deployed, aiming to make software releases a reliable, predictable process. In &amp;quot;Continuous Delivery: Reliable Software Releases through Build, Test, and Deployment Automation,&amp;quot; authors David Farley and Jez Humble provide a comprehensive guide to implementing CD practices effectively. This book is part of the Addison-Wesley Signature Series and offers detailed insights into achieving efficient, low-risk software deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/continuous_delivery.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2010 by David Farley and Jez Humble&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from The Phoenix Project</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-the-phoenix-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-the-phoenix-project/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;the-phoenix-project&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Phoenix Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Phoenix Project: A Novel About IT, DevOps, and Helping Your Business Win&amp;quot; by Gene Kim, Kevin Behr, and George Spafford is a revolutionary book that uses a narrative style to illustrate the principles of DevOps and how they can transform IT operations to drive business success. Through the story of Parts Unlimited, the authors demonstrate the challenges and triumphs of implementing DevOps practices in a real-world setting.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
