<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership on Marcus Vechiato</title>
    <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leadership on Marcus Vechiato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Insights from The Staff Engineer&#39;s Path</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-the-staff-engineers-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-the-staff-engineers-path/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2022 by Tanya Reilly
The Staff Engineer&amp;rsquo;s Path: A Guide For Individual Contributors Navigating Growth and Change
The Staff Engineer&amp;rsquo;s Path Introduction In the world of technology, career paths often lead to management roles. However, many engineers prefer to remain as individual contributors while advancing their careers. &amp;ldquo;The Staff Engineer&amp;rsquo;s Path: A Guide for Individual Contributors Navigating Growth and Change&amp;rdquo; by Tanya Reilly provides a roadmap for those aiming to excel as senior technical leaders without transitioning into management.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Working Backwards: Insights, Stories, and Secrets from Inside Amazon</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-working-backwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-working-backwards/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2021 by Colin Bryar &amp;amp; Bill Carr
Working Backwards Introduction &amp;ldquo;Working Backwards: Insights, Stories, and Secrets from Inside Amazon&amp;rdquo; by Colin Bryar and Bill Carr offers an insider’s perspective on the unique principles and processes that have driven Amazon&amp;rsquo;s success. The authors, both former Amazon executives, provide a detailed account of how the company&amp;rsquo;s culture and methodologies can be applied to achieve extraordinary results in any organisation.
Summary Part One: Being Amazonian Chapter 1: Building Blocks: Leadership Principles and Mechanisms This chapter introduces Amazon&amp;rsquo;s 14 Leadership Principles, which are central to the company&amp;rsquo;s culture and decision-making processes.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Ego Free Leadership: Ending the Unconscious Habits that Hijack Your Business</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-ego-free-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-ego-free-leadership/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2017 by Brandon Black &amp;amp; Shayne Hughes
Ego Free Leadership Introduction &amp;ldquo;Ego Free Leadership: Ending the Unconscious Habits that Hijack Your Business&amp;rdquo; by Brandon Black and Shayne Hughes provides a powerful exploration into how ego-driven behaviours can derail leadership and organisational success. Through the story of Brandon Black’s tenure as CEO of Encore Capital and his collaboration with executive coach Shayne Hughes, the book offers profound insights into overcoming ego to foster a culture of authenticity and high performance.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from No rules rules: Netflix and the culture of reinvention</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-no-rules-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-no-rules-rules/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2020 by Reed Hastings and Erin Meyer
No Rules Rules Introduction In &amp;ldquo;No Rules Rules: Netflix and the Culture of Reinvention,&amp;rdquo; Reed Hastings and Erin Meyer explore the unique and unconventional management philosophies that have made Netflix one of the most innovative and successful companies in the world. By prioritising freedom and responsibility over traditional corporate controls, Netflix has continuously reinvented itself to adapt to the changing needs of its global audience.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Ask Your Developer</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-ask-your-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-ask-your-developer/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2021 by Jeff Lawson
Ask Your Developer Introduction In the digital age, businesses need to adapt quickly to remain competitive. &amp;ldquo;Ask Your Developer&amp;rdquo; by Jeff Lawson, the CEO of Twilio, provides a roadmap for leveraging software developers&amp;rsquo; expertise to drive innovation and success. Lawson emphasizes the importance of integrating developers into business decision-making processes and creating an environment that fosters creativity and experimentation.
Summary Part I: Why Developers Matter More Than Ever Chapter 1: Build vs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from The Manager&#39;s Path</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-managers-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-managers-path/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ![image](/obsidian/the managers path.jpg) 2017 by Camile Fournier
The Manager&amp;rsquo;s Path: A Guide for Tech Leaders Navigating
The Manager&amp;rsquo;s Path Introduction &amp;ldquo;The Manager&amp;rsquo;s Path&amp;rdquo; by Camille Fournier is a comprehensive guide for those pursuing a career in engineering management. Fournier, drawing from her experiences, provides a structured roadmap for transitioning from an engineer to a manager and beyond. This book is a valuable resource not only for new managers but also for seasoned leaders seeking to refine their skills.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Remote: Office not Required</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-remote/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2013 by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson
Remote: Office Not Required Overview I remember the days when working from home was a rare privilege, reserved for special circumstances. Fast forward to today, remote work has become a norm, a necessity even, due to technological advancements and recent global events. This shift intrigued me, and it was a recommendation from my friend Eduardo that led me to &amp;ldquo;Remote: Office Not Required&amp;rdquo; by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from The Five Dysfunctions of a Team</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-the-five-dysfunctions-of-a-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-the-five-dysfunctions-of-a-team/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            by Patric Lencioni
Sure, I&amp;rsquo;ll add page numbers to the quotes and ensure the blog post reflects the detailed structure of the book accurately.
Insights from &amp;ldquo;The Five Dysfunctions of a Team&amp;rdquo; by Patrick Lencioni
The Five Dysfunctions of a Team Overview This book, presented as a leadership fable, delves into the core issues that impede teamwork and provides actionable insights to overcome these challenges. I chose this book to gain a deeper understanding of team dynamics and to find practical strategies to foster a more collaborative environment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
