<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Observability on Marcus Vechiato</title>
    <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/observability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Observability on Marcus Vechiato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/observability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Learning eBPF: Programmatically Extend the Linux Kernel</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20240515-book-insights-ebpf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20240515-book-insights-ebpf/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2023 by Liz Rice
Learning eBPF: Programming the Linux Kernel for Enhanced Observability, Networking, and Security
Learning eBPF Introduction In the realm of cloud-native infrastructure, eBPF (extended Berkeley Packet Filter) has emerged as a revolutionary technology. By allowing developers to write custom code that dynamically changes kernel behavior, eBPF has paved the way for a new generation of security, observability, and networking tools. In &amp;ldquo;Learning eBPF: Programming the Linux Kernel for Enhanced Observability, Networking, and Security,&amp;rdquo; Liz Rice provides a comprehensive guide to understanding and utilizing eBPF.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Observability Engineering: Achieving Production Excellence</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20221202-book-observability-engineering-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20221202-book-observability-engineering-2022/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2022 by Charity Majors &amp;amp; Liz Fong-Jones &amp;amp; George Miranda
Observability Engineering Introduction In the rapidly evolving landscape of software development and IT operations, ensuring system reliability and performance is paramount. &amp;ldquo;Observability Engineering&amp;rdquo; by Charity Majors, Liz Fong-Jones, and George Miranda provides a comprehensive guide to achieving production excellence through observability. This book explores the principles, practices, and tools necessary to understand and improve system behavior, making it an essential read for software engineers and site reliability engineers (SREs).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
