<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Marcus Vechiato</title><link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Marcus Vechiato</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Calculating 3D Print Costs with Spoolman API and Python</title><link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/calculating-3d-print-costs-with-spoolman-api-and-python/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/calculating-3d-print-costs-with-spoolman-api-and-python/</guid><description>
&lt;p>As a 3D printing enthusiast, I've often grappled with accurately calculating the cost of my prints. While slicers provide estimates of filament usage, they don't account for the actual cost of the filament used, especially when dealing with multiple spools or varying filament prices. To solve this, I developed a Python script that calculates the real cost of a 3D print by leveraging the Spoolman API.
In this blog post, I'll walk you through the motivation behind the project, the features of the script, and how you can use it to accurately estimate your 3D printing costs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Insights from Intro To Python Programming</title><link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-intro-to-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-intro-to-python/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="intro-to-python-programming-beginners-guide-series">&lt;strong>Intro To Python Programming: Beginners Guide Series&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>As a parent and mentor, I’m always on the lookout for resources to inspire and educate young minds. My son recently expressed an interest in learning Python, and I also help kids at a coding club take their first steps into programming. These two motivations led me to John Elder’s &lt;em>Intro to Python Programming&lt;/em>. This book promises to make coding approachable and fun for beginners, which aligns perfectly with my goals. Elder’s conversational tone and hands-on approach provide an excellent foundation for young learners and anyone embarking on their coding journey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Code Club - Quiz Controlled LEDs</title><link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/code-club---quiz-controlled-leds-with-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/code-club---quiz-controlled-leds-with-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="quiz-controlled-leds-with-raspberry-pi">&lt;strong>Quiz Controlled LEDs with Raspberry Pi&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Here's a challenge design for someone learning Python with a Raspberry Pi that incorporates asking questions and controlling LEDs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objective">&lt;strong>Objective:&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Create a Python-based LED game where players answer questions. Correct answers turn on a green LED, while wrong answers flash a red LED multiple times.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="code_club_thumbjpeg">![[code_club_thumb.jpeg]]&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="requirements">&lt;strong>Requirements:&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="hardware">&lt;strong>Hardware:&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Raspberry Pi (with GPIO capabilities)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 green LED for correct answers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 red LED for incorrect answers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 330Ω resistors&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Breadboard and jumper wires&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="python-concepts">&lt;strong>Python Concepts:&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>if&lt;/code>/&lt;code>else&lt;/code> statements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Loops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Functions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Basic GPIO control&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-overview">&lt;strong>Challenge Overview:&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="game-rules">Game Rules:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The game asks 5 multiple-choice questions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Players respond by entering the correct letter (e.g., A, B, C).
If the answer is correct:
The green LED lights up for 1 second.
The player gets a congratulatory message.
If the answer is incorrect:
The red LED flashes 3 times.
A message tells the player the correct answer.
The game ends with a score summary.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="steps">&lt;strong>Steps:&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="1-setup-the-leds">1. &lt;strong>Setup the LEDs&lt;/strong>:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Connect the LEDs to two GPIO pins (e.g., GPIO17 and GPIO18).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use resistors to protect the LEDs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Connect the cathode (short leg) of each LED to the ground (negative -).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>![[ledquiz_boardbred.png]]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Insights from 20 Easy Raspberry Pi Projects</title><link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-20-easy-raspberry-pi-projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-20-easy-raspberry-pi-projects/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="20-easy-raspberry-pi-projects">&lt;strong>20 Easy Raspberry Pi Projects&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>When I first discovered the Raspberry Pi, its versatility felt like a door to endless possibilities. &lt;em>20 Easy Raspberry Pi Projects&lt;/em> by Rui and Sara Santos exemplifies this sentiment by transforming this tiny computer into a toolkit for creativity. The book is packed with practical and entertaining projects, each designed to enhance your programming and electronics skills.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I chose this book to explore ways to improve IoT experiments and to inspire ideas for the code club and my son. Whether you’re new to electronics or an experienced maker, the projects in this book will leave you brimming with ideas. Here's an in-depth look at each project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Insights from Python Basics</title><link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-python-basics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-python-basics/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="python-basics-a-practical-introduction-to-python-3">&lt;strong>Python Basics: A Practical introduction to Python 3&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>When my son expressed interest in coding, it reignited my passion for introducing Python to others. This book, &lt;em>Python Basics: A Practical Introduction to Python 3&lt;/em>, is now part of the &amp;quot;Code Club&amp;quot; learning list—a collection of resources aimed at helping children at the club (and my son) discover the joy of Python.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Written by the Real Python team, this book serves as an excellent entry point for anyone new to programming. It breaks down Python’s fundamentals into digestible lessons, providing real-world examples and coding exercises. Whether you're a complete beginner or brushing up on basics, this book offers the tools to transform curiosity into skill. Readers can expect to learn the essentials of Python programming and gain confidence in solving practical problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Insights from Flask Web Development, Second Edition</title><link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-flask-web-development/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-flask-web-development/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="flask-web-development">&lt;strong>Flask Web Development&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I picked up &amp;quot;Flask Web Development&amp;quot; by Miguel Grinberg as part of my journey to deepen my understanding of web application development with Python. Having some experience with Django, I was curious to explore the micro-framework approach offered by Flask, known for its simplicity and flexibility. This book promised a hands-on guide to building web applications using Flask, which I hoped would help me apply these concepts in real-world projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Insights from Fluent Python, second edition</title><link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-fluent-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-fluent-python/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="fluent-python-clear-concise-and-effective-programming">&lt;strong>Fluent Python: Clear, Concise, and Effective Programming&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Welcome to our deep dive into &lt;em>Fluent Python&lt;/em> by Luciano Ramalho. In this post, we'll explore key concepts and insights from the book that will help you master Python programming. Whether you're a beginner or an experienced developer, this book offers valuable lessons on writing idiomatic Python code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Fluent Python&lt;/em> by Luciano Ramalho is a comprehensive guide that delves into the depths of Python programming, offering insights and practical advice on writing idiomatic and efficient Python code.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>