<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Platform Engineering on Marcus Vechiato</title>
    <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/platform-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Platform Engineering on Marcus Vechiato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/platform-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Plaftform Engineering</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-plafform-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-plafform-engineering/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;platform-engineering-a-guide-for-technical-product-and-people-leaders&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platform Engineering: A Guide for Technical, Product, and People Leaders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first came across the idea of platform engineering, I realised how critical it is for scaling organisations to manage shared infrastructure and tools effectively. Camille Fournier and Ian Nowland&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Platform Engineering&lt;/em&gt; goes beyond theory, offering actionable strategies for building cohesive, user-centric platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book resonated with me as someone passionate about improving engineering systems. It provides a structured approach to handling platform challenges, from team organisation to operational excellence. If you&#39;re a leader in the tech space, this guide is a treasure trove of insights to streamline complexity while fostering innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Crossplane: The Cloud Native Control Plane</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-crossplane-the-cloud-native-control-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-crossplane-the-cloud-native-control-plane/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;crossplane-the-cloud-native-control-plane&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crossplane: The Cloud Native Control Plane&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a DevOps enthusiast, I&#39;ve always been fascinated by the potential of cloud-native technologies to streamline and enhance our workflows. Recently, I picked up &amp;quot;Crossplane: The Cloud Native Control Plane&amp;quot; by Viktor Farcic, and it has been an enlightening journey. This book delves into the intricacies of Crossplane, a project that democratizes the powerful capabilities traditionally reserved for major cloud providers. By abstracting away complexity and allowing for custom control planes, Crossplane stands out as a transformative tool for modern infrastructure management. I chose this book to deepen my understanding of how Crossplane can help create a seamless, scalable, and efficient cloud infrastructure tailored to specific organizational needs.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Platform Engineering on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-platform-engineering-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-platform-engineering-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;platform-engineering-on-kubernetes&#34;&gt;Platform Engineering on Kubernetes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Platform Engineering on Kubernetes&amp;quot; by Mauricio Salatino provides a comprehensive guide to leveraging Kubernetes for platform engineering. This book explores the intricacies of building and maintaining platforms on top of Kubernetes, focusing on the needs of development teams and the challenges of cloud-native environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/book_platform_engineering_kubernetes.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2022 by Mauricio Salatino&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/mindmap_platform_engineering_k8s.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-rise-of-platforms-on-top-of-kubernetes&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The Rise of Platforms on Top of Kubernetes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter introduces the concept of platforms and their significance. It explains why platforms are essential for organisations and discusses the advantages of building platforms on top of Kubernetes. The chapter also outlines the challenges associated with platform engineering and the need for a &amp;quot;walking skeleton&amp;quot; to demonstrate platform concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from End-to-End Automation with Kubernetes and Crossplane</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-end-to-end-automation-with-kubernetes-and-crossplane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-end-to-end-automation-with-kubernetes-and-crossplane/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This book is an essential read for cloud architects, platform engineers, infrastructure operators, and Kubernetes enthusiasts. Arun Ramakani expertly navigates the intricate world of infrastructure automation, providing readers with a comprehensive understanding of Crossplane and its integration with Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;image&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;https://blog.vechiato.cc/obsidian/end2end_automation_k8s_crossplane.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

2022 by Arun Ramakani&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B09ZJ1NZRB&#34;&gt;End-to-End Automation with Kubernetes and Crossplane: Develop a control plane-based platform for unified infrastructure, services, and application automation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the ever-evolving landscape of cloud-native infrastructure, Kubernetes has emerged as a dominant force, revolutionising the way organisations deploy and manage applications. However, the complexity of infrastructure automation has often been a bottleneck. Enter Crossplane—a powerful extension of Kubernetes designed to bring the same level of automation to infrastructure provisioning and management. In &amp;quot;End-to-End Automation with Kubernetes and Crossplane,&amp;quot; Arun Ramakani guides us through building a control plane-based platform for unified infrastructure, services, and application automation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on My Presentation at the London SRE Meetup</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/london-sre-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/london-sre-meetup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;I recently had the wonderful opportunity to present at the London SRE Meetup, and I&#39;m excited to share the experience with you all. The presentation, titled &amp;quot;Working Together: SRE and Platform Engineering,&amp;quot; focused on the synergy between site reliability engineering and platform engineering to enhance operational efficiencies and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to have engaged with so many knowledgeable professionals and enthusiasts who are passionate about improving systems and operations. The discussions and interactions were enlightening, and I hope they were as beneficial for attendees as they were for me.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
