<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Platform Engineering on Marcus Vechiato</title>
    <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/platform-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Platform Engineering on Marcus Vechiato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/platform-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Platform Engineering on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-platform-engineering-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-platform-engineering-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2022 by Mauricio Salatino
Platform Engineering on Kubernetes
Platform Engineering on Kubernetes Introduction &amp;ldquo;Platform Engineering on Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; by Mauricio Salatino provides a comprehensive guide to leveraging Kubernetes for platform engineering. This book explores the intricacies of building and maintaining platforms on top of Kubernetes, focusing on the needs of development teams and the challenges of cloud-native environments.
Summary Chapter 1: The Rise of Platforms on Top of Kubernetes This chapter introduces the concept of platforms and their significance.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from End-to-End Automation with Kubernetes and Crossplane</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-end-to-end-automation-with-kubernetes-and-crossplane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/book-end-to-end-automation-with-kubernetes-and-crossplane/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2022 by Arun Ramakani
End-to-End Automation with Kubernetes and Crossplane: Develop a control plane-based platform for unified infrastructure, services, and application automation
Introduction In the ever-evolving landscape of cloud-native infrastructure, Kubernetes has emerged as a dominant force, revolutionizing the way organizations deploy and manage applications. However, the complexity of infrastructure automation has often been a bottleneck. Enter Crossplane—a powerful extension of Kubernetes designed to bring the same level of automation to infrastructure provisioning and management.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on My Presentation at the London SRE Meetup</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20230523-london-sre-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20230523-london-sre-meetup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I recently had the wonderful opportunity to present at the London SRE Meetup, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share the experience with you all. The presentation, titled &amp;ldquo;Working Together: SRE and Platform Engineering,&amp;rdquo; focused on the synergy between site reliability engineering and platform engineering to enhance operational efficiencies and reliability.
I am pleased to have engaged with so many knowledgeable professionals and enthusiasts who are passionate about improving systems and operations.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
