<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code Club on Marcus Vechiato</title>
    <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/code-club/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code Club on Marcus Vechiato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/code-club/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Insights from 20 Easy Raspberry Pi Projects</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-20-easy-raspberry-pi-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-20-easy-raspberry-pi-projects/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;20-easy-raspberry-pi-projects&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20 Easy Raspberry Pi Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first discovered the Raspberry Pi, its versatility felt like a door to endless possibilities. &lt;em&gt;20 Easy Raspberry Pi Projects&lt;/em&gt; by Rui and Sara Santos exemplifies this sentiment by transforming this tiny computer into a toolkit for creativity. The book is packed with practical and entertaining projects, each designed to enhance your programming and electronics skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose this book to explore ways to improve IoT experiments and to inspire ideas for the code club and my son. Whether you’re new to electronics or an experienced maker, the projects in this book will leave you brimming with ideas. Here&#39;s an in-depth look at each project.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Python for Kids</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-python-for-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/book-python-for-kids/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;python-for-kids-a-playful-introduction-to-programming&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python for Kids: A Playful Introduction to Programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started programming, I wished for resources that made the journey exciting and approachable. &lt;em&gt;Python for Kids&lt;/em&gt; by Jason R. Briggs is just that—a vibrant, engaging introduction to Python that teaches through play and creativity. This book combines accessible explanations with hands-on examples, guiding readers to build games, draw graphics, and explore Python’s powerful features. Whether you’re a curious child, a parent, or an adult beginner, this book offers a fun and rewarding way to learn coding.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Host Your Website for Free as friendly as possible for beginners</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/cloudflare-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/post/cloudflare-pages/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-host-your-website-for-free-no-git-required&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Host Your Website for Free No Git required!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you’ve just learned HTML and CSS and are eager to put your website online, Cloudflare Pages is an excellent, beginner-friendly way to host your site for free. This post was inspired by my own son, who recently asked me for a way to publish his site that looked a bit more professional than the usual coding platform links. Like him, you might be looking for something simple yet polished to showcase your work. This guide will walk you through the process without needing to know Git or any advanced setups.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
