<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sre on Marcus Vechiato</title>
    <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/sre/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sre on Marcus Vechiato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vechiato.cc/tags/sre/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Chaos Engineering: System Resiliency in Practice</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20240626-book-chaos-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20240626-book-chaos-engineering/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2020 by Casey Rosenthal, Nora Jones
Chaos Engineering Introduction: Birth of Chaos The book begins with the history of Chaos Engineering, originating from Netflix. Rosenthal and Jones describe the transition from datacenter architecture to cloud infrastructure, highlighting challenges and the necessity of Chaos Engineering for improving system resiliency.
Summary Part I: Setting the Stage Chapter 1: Encountering Complex Systems This chapter discusses the inherent complexity of modern software systems and the need for a new approach to handle unexpected failures.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Learning eBPF: Programmatically Extend the Linux Kernel</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20240515-book-insights-ebpf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20240515-book-insights-ebpf/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2023 by Liz Rice
Learning eBPF: Programming the Linux Kernel for Enhanced Observability, Networking, and Security
Learning eBPF Introduction In the realm of cloud-native infrastructure, eBPF (extended Berkeley Packet Filter) has emerged as a revolutionary technology. By allowing developers to write custom code that dynamically changes kernel behavior, eBPF has paved the way for a new generation of security, observability, and networking tools. In &amp;ldquo;Learning eBPF: Programming the Linux Kernel for Enhanced Observability, Networking, and Security,&amp;rdquo; Liz Rice provides a comprehensive guide to understanding and utilizing eBPF.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on My Presentation at the London SRE Meetup</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20230523-london-sre-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20230523-london-sre-meetup/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I recently had the wonderful opportunity to present at the London SRE Meetup, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share the experience with you all. The presentation, titled &amp;ldquo;Working Together: SRE and Platform Engineering,&amp;rdquo; focused on the synergy between site reliability engineering and platform engineering to enhance operational efficiencies and reliability.
I am pleased to have engaged with so many knowledgeable professionals and enthusiasts who are passionate about improving systems and operations.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Establishing SRE Foundations</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20230120-book-establishing-sre-foundations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20230120-book-establishing-sre-foundations/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Establishing SRE Foundations: A Step-by-Step Guide to Introducing Site Reliability Engineering in Software Delivery Organizations
Establishing SRE Foundations Introduction &amp;ldquo;Establishing SRE Foundations: A Step-by-Step Guide&amp;rdquo; by Vladyslav Ukis provides a comprehensive framework for implementing Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) in software delivery organisations. Drawing from his extensive experience, Ukis outlines practical steps and methodologies to enhance reliability and operational efficiency in software systems.
Summary Chapter 1: Introduction to SRE The first chapter introduces the concept of Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) and its importance in modern software development.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Observability Engineering: Achieving Production Excellence</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20221202-book-observability-engineering-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20221202-book-observability-engineering-2022/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2022 by Charity Majors &amp;amp; Liz Fong-Jones &amp;amp; George Miranda
Observability Engineering Introduction In the rapidly evolving landscape of software development and IT operations, ensuring system reliability and performance is paramount. &amp;ldquo;Observability Engineering&amp;rdquo; by Charity Majors, Liz Fong-Jones, and George Miranda provides a comprehensive guide to achieving production excellence through observability. This book explores the principles, practices, and tools necessary to understand and improve system behavior, making it an essential read for software engineers and site reliability engineers (SREs).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Database Reliability Engineering: Designing and Operating Resilient Database Systems</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20200921-book-database-reliability-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20200921-book-database-reliability-engineering/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2017 by Laine Campbell &amp;amp; Charity Majors
Database Reliability Engineering Introduction &amp;ldquo;Database Reliability Engineering&amp;rdquo; by Laine Campbell and Charity Majors is a comprehensive guide on how to design, build, and manage resilient database systems. The book emphasizes the importance of reliability in database operations and introduces the role of a Database Reliability Engineer (DBRE) who combines database expertise with software engineering principles to ensure robust data management.
Summary Part 1: Introducing Database Reliability Engineering Chapter 1: Introducing Database Reliability Engineering This chapter sets the stage by defining the role of a Database Reliability Engineer and the need for reliability engineering in database management.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Seeking SRE</title>
      <link>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20200622-book-seeking-sre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vechiato.cc/blog/20200622-book-seeking-sre/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2018 by David Blank–edelman
Seeking SRE: Conversations about running production systems at scale
Seeking SRE Introduction Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) has become a fundamental practice in ensuring the reliability and efficiency of large-scale production systems. &amp;ldquo;Seeking SRE: Conversations About Running Production Systems at Scale&amp;rdquo; by David N. Blank-Edelman offers a comprehensive exploration of SRE practices through a series of insightful essays and interviews. This book serves as an invaluable resource for anyone involved in managing complex systems, from seasoned SREs to those new to the field.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
